awwapp.com 2019-02-24

# A web whiteboard

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. is a hosted web application ("Service") developed and maintained by A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC., doing business as "A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC.".

We care about your personal data you entrust with us. Demonstrating A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC.’s engagement in personal data protection we are bringing you the key facts about how we handle personal data processing in A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC.

#### We are GDPR ready and compliant

GDPR is the REGULATION (EU) 2016/679 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).

#### Data Protection Officer

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. is a data controller and a processor of personal data provided in Service.

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. has its headquarters in the USA so we have appointed a representative and internal data protection officer ("DPO") for you to contact if you have any questions or concerns about A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC.’s personal data policies or practices. You can reach out to our Data Protection Officer at hello@awwapp.com.

#### What do we do

We provide a web application for online collaboration. The main activity of A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. is enabling collaborated drawing and writing on a virtual whiteboard that is shared with other computers connected to the same board.

In order to perform our Service we process:

  1. • (as a data controller) internet protocol (IP) of everyone who visits our service ("Visitor")
  2. • (as a data controller) personal data of our customers (users of Service acting as Account Owner, Administrators, Agents - jointly referred to as ("You"));

#### How do we collect personal data

 **Visitors data**

Where the website is used for informational purposes, so that You do not register as a user of the website or transmit other information to us, we do not collect any personal data, with the exception of the data which Your browser transmits to us in order to allow You to access the website.

This data is:

  1. • IP address
  2. • Date and time of the query
  3. • Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)
  4. • Content of the request (specific site)
  5. • Access status/HTTP status code
  6. • Volume of data transferred each time
  7. • Website from which the request comes
  8. • Browser
  9. • Operating system and its interface
  10. • Language and version of the browser software.

 **Your personal data**

  1. • Name
  2. • Email address
  3. • Your professional segment
  4. • Billing information - which we do not store ourselves, we use Stripe for this purpose to ensure best security of Your billing information
  5. • Internet protocol (IP)
  6. • API token
  7. • Cookies
  8. • Local storage

We collects personal data (name, email) during registration process and when You add new Agents. A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. We collect information how You use our Service, i.e. which features You use the most, which pages You visit, which buttons You click. We use cookies – you can find more info in the Cookies section.

We enable You to use third parties usage like Google Classroom.

If anything is unclear please contact our DPO at hello@awwapp.com

#### What are the legal grounds for processing data

We process Your data either on contractual ground (processing is necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or in order to take steps at Your request prior to entering into a contract) or when You have given us Your explicit consent.

What are the purposes of processing data:

 **Your personal data**

  1. • **Service performance including its development**  \- email, name, profession segment, billing information, API token, cookies, internet protocol (IP)
  2. • **Marketing**  \- email, name, profession segment

Service performance purposes means all data processing relevant to providing You with Service. This is information which we need for creating an account for You (name, e-mail address, profession segment, billing information) but also to develop and maintain our Service (cookies, API token, internet protocol (IP). A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. analyzes trends, tracks Your movements so we can adjust Service to Your needs.

Marketing purposes mean that we want to inform You about our new features and products and send You a newsletter regarding it via email.

You can always withdraw Your consent – more at Right to withdraw your consent here.

## Tracking and Profiling

 **Your personal data**

We use online tracking which means A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files and databases. The information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of the A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC.s’ website, including a history of the pages You visit in A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. analyzes trends, tracks Your movements, and gathers this information in order to make better decisions in terms of product development, so it better suits Your needs and also for assisting us in debugging issues You report to us via our own support channels.

Although online tracking is an automated process in which we collect personal data (Your movements online) A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. does not make any predictions or draws no conclusion about an individual – You – on that account. We use online tracking only for Service development. We don’t create any profiles nor do we make any decisions concerning You that are made based on online tracking. We are not profiling You.

In case of any doubts please contact us at hello@awwapp.com

 **Cookies**

A cookie is a small amount of data which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to Your browser from a web site’s computers and is stored on Your computers hard drive. Cookies are required to use A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. in order to uniquely identify Your browser and user preferences while logged in. We use non-permanent cookies that last for up to two weeks, after which You will be required to log in to the Service again.

You can control and/or delete cookies as You wish using Your browser preferences. You can delete all cookies that are already on Your computer and You can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If You do this, however, You may have to manually adjust some preferences every time You visit A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. and some services and functionalities may not work.

## Who do we disclose Your data to

We cooperate with several third parties, however we do not disclose any personal data to them without Your demand or consent. If You wish to use any of third-parties services You will be asked to agree to third parties’ terms and conditions (including privacy policies).

We are not liable for third parties compliance to data protection however we do not cooperate with any entity which does not demonstrate strong data protection care.

The list of third parties are:

  1. • Google
  2. • Facebook
  3. • Twitter
  4. • Sentry

## Where and to whom do we transfer Your data

In order to maintain and develop Service A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. engages another entities. If you live in one of EU/EEA countries you gave us general written authorisation in Data Processing Agreement.

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. notifies You if we intend to change the list so You have the opportunity to object to such changes.

## Your rights

 **Access**

You have a right to be informed about Your personal data processing, including the source of Your data collection, purpose of its processing and how long it will be stored.

If You have any question regarding Your personal data please contact our DPO at hello@awwapp.com

 **Rectification**

You have a right to access and change Your personal data provided during registration or creating an account. You can do this in the Profile section of Your Account Settings.

 **Erasure ("right to be forgotten"):**

In line with GDPR enforcement of the right to be forgotten, A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. introduces internal procedures which will streamline this process.

In other words You (as an Account owner and/or Admin) can decide whether You wish to permanently delete a whole account, a user account or just specific personal data. If You decide so the process will be irreversible.

Deletion can be performed by either using a "delete" function next to an appropriate piece of data in the Service (for example, Delete Ticket) or by contacting us on hello@awwapp.com when a built-in option is not available.

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. reserves the right to refuse permanent deletion for a legitimate reason, in particular but not limited to if current business affairs are not yet finished.

 **Restriction on processing**

You have a right to demand ceasing processing your data or restricting its processing with respect to exceptions set forth in art. 18 GDPR.

If You have any question regarding Your restriction rights please contact our DPO at hello@awwapp.com

 **Portability**

If You need to export/import data to the Service in a way which is not available, please contact us at hello@awwapp.com so we can help You with Your custom needs.

However, we also have exposed an API which allows You to easily access Your data in a portable way as well import data from other systems.

You can read more about the API here.

 **Right to withdraw consent**

You always can withdraw Your consent for processing Your data for marketing. To do so just contact us at hello@awwapp.com.

 **Lodge a complaint**

You have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if You have concerns about how A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. processes Your personal data. For more information please contact our DPO at hello@awwapp.com.

## Cross-border US - EU transfer

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. is established in the United States. Information we collect from You and on Your behalf will be processed in the United States.

The United States has not sought nor received a finding of "adequacy" from the European Union under Article 45 of the GDPR. A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. relies on derogations for specific situations as set forth in Article 49 of the GDPR. In particular, A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. collects and transfers to the U.S. personal data only: with Your consent; to perform a contract with You; or to fulfil a compelling legitimate interest of A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. in a manner that does not outweigh Your nor Your customers’ rights and freedoms. A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. endeavours to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of Your and Your customers’ personal data and to use it only consistent with Your relationship with A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. and the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

## Data storage

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. stores Your and Your customers’ personal data on the servers of the cloud-based database management services A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. engages, located in the United States. A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. is hosted at Linode datacenters which announced compliance with GDPR. For more information on their servers and security, please see [Linode compliance page](https://www.linode.com/compliance).

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. notifies You if we intend to change the list so You have the opportunity to object to such changes.

For more information regarding data storage contact our DPO at hello@awwapp.com.

#### Retention

We keep all Your data that You have provided to us for the duration of Your business relationship with us and we remove data:

  1. • at Your explicit request (either via clicking the delete button next to a particular piece of data or via an email request to staviti hello@awwapp.com)
  2. • after You cancel Your account, at which point we remove Your data. This process takes up to 30 days to ensure all Your data is expunged from the system

Most of personal data is deleted once You demand it or our business relation is ceased, however we keep Your name and email address longer until all possible business affairs are finished.

For more information please contact our DPO at hello@awwapp.com.

## Security of data

We are committed to ensuring the best security for You, which means choosing the best hosting providers and data storage solutions, including those having ISO 27001 and PCI Level 1 certifications. We ensure encryption of communication not only between You and our servers but also internally between parts of our Service.

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. restricts access to Your personal data to those employees who need to know that information to provide benefits or services to You. We maintain an internal Security Policy which ensures that all sensitive information is always transferred using secure, encrypted channels. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of Your information. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce our employees' privacy responsibilities.

## Legal obligations regarding data.

A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. discloses personal data we process if necessary for the requirement to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

## Changes and updates to the Privacy Policy

As A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC. changes from time to time, this Privacy Policy is expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the Privacy Policy at any time, for any reason. We will inform You about that change by sending to You an email. Remember to check our Privacy Policy website.

## Contact & Questions

In case of any queries please contact A WEB WHITEBOARD, INC.’s DPO at hello@awwapp.com.
